Ali Taee - Front-end Developer

CONTACTS

Ali.Taee.72@gmail.com
Linkedin
Stack overflow
Github

SUMMARY

As a Front-end Developer with more than 4 years of experience in building responsive websites and web applications, I am always looking for a way to improve my work and team performance, from adding documents and unit tests to contributing my knowledge and giving feedback in code reviews. I enjoy Music, Photography, Novels, Travel and Technology.

SKILLS

Jira, Scrum, Agile Development, HTML, CSS, CSS Processors, Responsive Design, JavaScript, TypeScript, JQuery, React, SPA, Gatsby, Next.Js, Redux, Socket.IO, REST API, E2E Testing, Unit Testing, Parcel.Js, Webpack, Git

EXPERIENCE

<u>Snappfood</u>, Tehran, Iran — Front-end Developer

February 2021 - Present

- Worked in a team of 10 people closely with designers, developers, QA engineers, scrum masters, and product managers using Scrum.
- Developed features and maintained the mobile applications using React, JavaScript, SCSS, and Redux-Saga.
- Developed features and maintained the desktop applications using React, TypeScript, Next.js,
 Storybook, Redux Toolkit, and styled-components.
- Created a document for onboarding new developers.

Pishgam Vista, Tehran, Iran — Front-end Developer

December 2019 - June 2021

- Created front-end projects using JavaScript, React, Material-UI, Redux-thunk, Socket.IO, REST API.
- Reduced development time by creating common components.
- Collaborated with 8 other group members of designers, developers, product owners.
- Debugged 3 large legacy codes and refactored them for better performance and clean code. Improved load time by 50%.

- Implemented dashboards for our internal projects using React.
- Converted UI landing design into responsive web page.
- Launched a game campaign with a team of developers and designers within a tight deadline, using Vue.js.
- Released video gallery using HTML, CSS, Flexbox, and JavaScript, it increased average session duration by 5%.

Arta Seo, Esfahan, Iran — Front-end Developer / WordPress Developer

March 2018 - February 2019

- Communicated with customers to create their responsive websites based on their needs.
- Converted UI designs into WordPress responsive websites.
- Introduced WordPress plugin development to the company.
- Mentored a team of 10 interns to learn HTML, CSS, and WordPress.
- Reduced data entry time to 30% by optimizing the website panel.

<u>Asr-e Digital</u>, Esfahan, Iran — WordPress Developer / Website Manager

February 2014 – January 2017

- Proposed creating a blog to publish product reviews and news in Technology, this led to improving Alexa rank 2 times.
- Directed 3 translators to translate English content to Persian and content editing according to SEO .
- Customized a blog using WordPress for better user experience.

EDUCATION

Safahan, Isfahan — Associate's degree

LANGUAGES

Persian (Native)

English (Advanced level)